




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design Patterns :: Introduction to Scratch</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/</link>
    <description>Design Patterns are commonly-used combinations of blocks</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ask and Set</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/02-ask-and-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/02-ask-and-set/</guid>
      <description>For many Scratch programs we find ourselves needing to ask the user questions and use thier answers later. If we need to ask more than one question, only the last answer is available in the answer block. The ask and set design pattern meets this need by prompting the user for an answer, then storing it in a variable:&#xA;Example For example, we might prompt the user for thier first and last names, and then greet them by both:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animated Move</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/03-animated-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/03-animated-move/</guid>
      <description>The move () steps immediately moves a sprite the specified number of steps. But what if we want that movement to be slower, animated over time? The various glide blocks provide smooth movement, but not in the direction the sprite is facing. Instead, we can emulate this movement with a combination of repeat (), move () steps, and wait () seconds blocks:&#xA;The total number of units moved is the product of the number of repeats and the movement in the block (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready and Go</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/04-get-ready-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/intro-scratch/04-design-patterns/04-get-ready-go/</guid>
      <description>Sprites in Scratch maintain thier state - which means that if the program was stopped with a sprite in a certain position, the next time the program is run, it will begin in that position. But for many Scratch projects, we want every sprite to start in a known position, regardless of where it last was.&#xA;One common pattern to accomplish this using messages is the Get Ready and Go design pattern.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>